<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</title>
    <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes Toward the Adoption of 2 Artificial Intelligence–Enabled Mental Health Tools Among Prospective Psychotherapists: Cross-sectional Study</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-06-attitudes-toward-the-adoption-of-2-artificial-intelligenceenabled-mental-health-tools-among-prospective-psychotherapists-cross-sectional-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-06-attitudes-toward-the-adoption-of-2-artificial-intelligenceenabled-mental-health-tools-among-prospective-psychotherapists-cross-sectional-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently conducted a study on the predictors of using AI-enabled mental health tools among psychology students and early practitioners. Here is a summary of our research:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;206 psychology students and psychotherapists in training were presented with graphic depictions of two specific AI-enabled mental health tools and their functioning mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We measured various factors related to the acceptance and use of these tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceived usefulness and social influence were strong predictors of intention to use the AI tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust and perceived ease of use had limited impact on the intention to use the tools (especially the treatment recommendation tool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive technology readiness positively affected the intention to use one tool, while AI anxiety negatively impacted the intention to use both tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our findings highlight the importance of perceived usefulness and social influence in driving the adoption of AI technology in mental health care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust and perceived ease of use may not be strong factors influencing the intention to use AI tools in this context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considering cognitive technology readiness can further promote the adoption of AI-enabled tools, while addressing AI anxiety is crucial in facilitating their utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study provides valuable insights for psychology students and early practitioners considering the integration of AI tools into their professional practice, and opens avenues for future research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpshumanfactorsjmirorg20231e46859&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://humanfactors.jmir.org/2023/1/e46859&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpshumanfactorsjmirorg20231e46859&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Mental Health Care with AI-Enabled Precision Psychiatry Tools: A Patent Review</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-02-advancing-mental-health-care-with-ai-enabled-precision-psychiatry-tools-a-patent-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-02-advancing-mental-health-care-with-ai-enabled-precision-psychiatry-tools-a-patent-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/wmr38&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View the pre-print here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thriving at work: An investigation of the independent and joint effects of vitality and learning on employee health</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-08-thriving-at-work-an-investigation-of-the-independent-and-joint-effects-of-vitality-and-learning-on-employee-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-08-thriving-at-work-an-investigation-of-the-independent-and-joint-effects-of-vitality-and-learning-on-employee-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thriving at work has been defined as employees’ joint sense of vitality and learning. Based on the socially
embedded model of thriving at work, we examine several competing operationalizations of thriving at
work. We hypothesize effects of (a) composite thriving, (b) separate vitality and learning scores, and (c)
the interaction between vitality and learning, and we explore effects of (d) the congruence between
vitality and learning on self-rated physical and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data came from n = 1,064 employees who
participated in a four-wave study with one-month time lags. Results of multilevel linear and polynomial
regression analyses showed that composite thriving was positively related to physical health, and
composite thriving and vitality were positively related to mental health at the within-person level. We
found no support for interaction or congruence effects. The findings provide limited support for the
assumed beneficial health effects of thriving on employees’ health.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implications for theory development
include the need to revise the role of vitality and learning as predictors of physical and mental health in
the model of thriving at work.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpswwwtandfonlinecomdoipdf1010801359432x20222102485&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/1359432X.2022.2102485&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpswwwtandfonlinecomdoipdf1010801359432x20222102485&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career planning and self-efficacy as predictors of students’ career-related worry</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-career-planning-and-self-efficacy-as-predictors-of-students-career-related-worry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-career-planning-and-self-efficacy-as-predictors-of-students-career-related-worry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shedding light on social-cognitive resources that mitigate master students’ experience of dysfunctional career-related worry before graduation.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the career self-management model (CSM; Lent &amp;amp; Brown, 2013), we investigated concurrent and time-lagged direct and mediated relationships between career planning, career-related self-efficacy, and career-related worry among a sample of 482 students shortly before graduation.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using data collected at three time points, a negative relationship was found between career planning (T1) and career-related worry (T3) via career-related self-efficacy (T2).
Our findings shed light on the role of career planning and career-related self-efficacy as malleable social-cognitive resources that diminish dysfunctional thinking before graduation in sequential order. The findings imply that career planning and career-related self-efficacy are relevant predictors of affective states and can be incorporated into the CSM.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpsjournalssagepubcomdoiabs10117708948453221078950&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08948453221078950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpsjournalssagepubcomdoiabs10117708948453221078950&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students&#39; Career exploration: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-students-career-exploration-a-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-students-career-exploration-a-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Greetings from the future!  --&gt;
&lt;!-- A lot has changed about blogdown, Hugo, and the Academic theme (now Wowchemy) since the time this post was written.  --&gt;
&lt;!-- An updated tutorial can now be found [here](/post/new-year-new-blogdown) 🎉 --&gt;
&lt;!--
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career exploration refers to the exploration of the environment and the self with the aim of gathering career-related information.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of Lent and Brown&amp;rsquo;s (2013) model of career self-management (CSM), the current meta-analysis examined the antecedents and outcomes of career exploration among college students (K = 109, N = 34,969 students).&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found support for the applicability of the CSM model to the context of students&amp;rsquo; career exploration. Specifically, positive associations were found for the association of the three core person-cognitive variables self-efficacy for career exploration and decision-making (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.52), outcome expectations (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.31), and career-exploratory goals (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.42) with career exploration. Results of path analyses suggest that the effects of both self-efficacy and outcome expectations on career exploration are mediated by career-exploratory goals. Further, in line with the CSM model, career exploration was positively related to career-related support (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.33) and negatively related to barriers (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = − 0.15). Moreover, career exploration was associated with important career-related outcomes, such as career decidedness (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.22), and perceived employability (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.35). Exploratory moderator analyses revealed that some relationships are influenced by sample (i.e., age, gender, cultural background) and measurement (e.g., publication date) characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-implies&#34;&gt;What this implies:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-implies&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings of this meta-analysis highlight several implications for the further development of the CSM model, future research on students&amp;rsquo; career exploration, and career development practice.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpswwwsciencedirectcomsciencearticlepiis0001879121001172&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879121001172&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpswwwsciencedirectcomsciencearticlepiis0001879121001172&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurs may experience errors as simultaneously challenging and threatening</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-entrepreneurs-may-experience-errors-as-simultaneously-challenging-and-threatening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-entrepreneurs-may-experience-errors-as-simultaneously-challenging-and-threatening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to transactional stress theory (TST), the extent to which entrepreneurs cope with errors by engaging in error damage control or ruminating about disengaging from their business goals depends on whether they interpret action errors as predominantly challenging or threatening.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using latent profile analysis (LPA), the current study investigates the existence of latent profiles of challenge and threat appraisal of entrepreneurial errors and their relationship with error damage control and rumination about business goal disengagement in a sample of 649 entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results identify five appraisal profiles characterized by different challenge and threat appraisal intensities. The levels of error damage control and rumination about business goal disengagement differed between the profiles. Specifically, entrepreneurs high in challenge and threat appraisal showed higher levels of both forms of coping than those low in appraisal. Entrepreneurs falling into a high challenge and low threat appraisal profile exhibited the lowest level of business goal disengagement. Still, they showed similar levels of error damage control to those high on challenge and threat appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs may experience action errors as challenging and threatening simultaneously. Error management approaches may be used to foster an atmosphere in which errors are appraised as learning opportunities rather than threats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thriving at work: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2020-06-thriving-at-work-a-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2020-06-thriving-at-work-a-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe height=&#39;454&#39; width=&#39;300&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/athletes/56021200/latest-rides/004c9101285c4f851fe9e6a73e2c796e0d68dbaa&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thriving at work refers to a positive psychological state characterized by a joint sense of vitality and learning.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of Spreitzer and colleagues&amp;rsquo; model, we present a comprehensive meta-analysis of antecedents and outcomes of thriving at work (K = 73 independent samples, N = 21,739 employees).&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results showed that thriving at work is associated with individual characteristics, such as psychological capital (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .47), proactive personality (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .58), positive affect (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .52), and work engagement (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .64). Positive associations were also found between thriving at work and relational characteristics, including supportive coworker behavior (rc = .42), supportive leadership behavior (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .44), and perceived organizational support (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .63). Moreover, thriving at work is related to important employee outcomes, including health-related outcomes such as burnout (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = −.53), attitudinal outcomes such as commitment (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .65), and performance-related outcomes such as task performance (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = .35). The results of relative weights analyses suggest that thriving exhibits small, albeit incremental predictive validity above and beyond positive affect and work engagement, for task performance, job satisfaction, subjective health, and burnout.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the findings of this meta-analysis support Spreitzer and colleagues&amp;rsquo; model and underscore the importance of thriving in the work context.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpsonlinelibrarywileycomdoifull101002job2375&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/job.2375&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpsonlinelibrarywileycomdoifull101002job2375&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


