<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>entrepreneurs on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</title>
    <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/categories/entrepreneurs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in entrepreneurs on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/categories/entrepreneurs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Financial stress and quit intention: the mediating role of entrepreneurs’ affective commitment</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2024-04-financial-stress-and-quit-intention-the-mediating-role-of-entrepreneurs-affective-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2024-04-financial-stress-and-quit-intention-the-mediating-role-of-entrepreneurs-affective-commitment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One primary reason why entrepreneurs abandon their entrepreneurial goals is due to pressing financial difficulties. In one experimental and two field studies, we investigated the relationship between entrepreneurs’ financial stress and their intention to quit their businesses. In line with the challenge–hindrance stressor (CHS) framework, all three studies showed a positive link between financial stress and quit intention, both concurrently and over time. Furthermore, drawing on self-determination theory (SDT), we found support for affective commitment (but not continuance commitment) to the entrepreneurial endeavors as a mediator of the relationship. The findings provide novel insights into financial stress as a relevant entrepreneurial hindrance stressor and the role of the emotional bond formed (and dissolved) between entrepreneurs and their jobs as the mediating mechanism. Practical suggestions include considering the affective commitment levels of entrepreneurs to enhance consultancy and decision-making in entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpslinkspringercomarticle101007s11365-024-00972-8&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11365-024-00972-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpslinkspringercomarticle101007s11365-024-00972-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge and threat appraisal of entrepreneurial errors: a latent profile analysis and examination of coping responses</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2024-02-challenge-and-threat-appraisal-of-entrepreneurial-errors-a-latent-profile-analysis-and-examination-of-coping-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2024-02-challenge-and-threat-appraisal-of-entrepreneurial-errors-a-latent-profile-analysis-and-examination-of-coping-responses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to transactional stress theory (TST), entrepreneurs&amp;rsquo; coping strategies, such as error damage control or rumination about disengaging from business goals, hinge on whether they view action errors as challenges or threats. Using latent profile analysis (LPA), the study explores distinct profiles of challenge and threat appraisals among 649 entrepreneurs and their links to coping behaviors. The findings reveal five appraisal profiles with varying levels of challenge and threat, highlighting differences in error damage control and rumination, and suggesting avenues for the further development of TST and developing effective error management interventions among entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpslinkspringercomarticle101007s12144-023-04370-1&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12144-023-04370-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpslinkspringercomarticle101007s12144-023-04370-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurs may experience errors as simultaneously challenging and threatening</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-entrepreneurs-may-experience-errors-as-simultaneously-challenging-and-threatening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2022-06-entrepreneurs-may-experience-errors-as-simultaneously-challenging-and-threatening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to transactional stress theory (TST), the extent to which entrepreneurs cope with errors by engaging in error damage control or ruminating about disengaging from their business goals depends on whether they interpret action errors as predominantly challenging or threatening.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using latent profile analysis (LPA), the current study investigates the existence of latent profiles of challenge and threat appraisal of entrepreneurial errors and their relationship with error damage control and rumination about business goal disengagement in a sample of 649 entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results identify five appraisal profiles characterized by different challenge and threat appraisal intensities. The levels of error damage control and rumination about business goal disengagement differed between the profiles. Specifically, entrepreneurs high in challenge and threat appraisal showed higher levels of both forms of coping than those low in appraisal. Entrepreneurs falling into a high challenge and low threat appraisal profile exhibited the lowest level of business goal disengagement. Still, they showed similar levels of error damage control to those high on challenge and threat appraisal.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs may experience action errors as challenging and threatening simultaneously. Error management approaches may be used to foster an atmosphere in which errors are appraised as learning opportunities rather than threats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


