<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</title>
    <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/categories/unified-theory-of-acceptance-and-use-of-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology on Anne-Kathrin Kleine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/categories/unified-theory-of-acceptance-and-use-of-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes Toward the Adoption of 2 Artificial Intelligence–Enabled Mental Health Tools Among Prospective Psychotherapists: Cross-sectional Study</title>
      <link>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-06-attitudes-toward-the-adoption-of-2-artificial-intelligenceenabled-mental-health-tools-among-prospective-psychotherapists-cross-sectional-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annekathrinkleine.netlify.app/blog/2023-06-attitudes-toward-the-adoption-of-2-artificial-intelligenceenabled-mental-health-tools-among-prospective-psychotherapists-cross-sectional-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently conducted a study on the predictors of using AI-enabled mental health tools among psychology students and early practitioners. Here is a summary of our research:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-did&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;206 psychology students and psychotherapists in training were presented with graphic depictions of two specific AI-enabled mental health tools and their functioning mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We measured various factors related to the acceptance and use of these tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;What we found:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceived usefulness and social influence were strong predictors of intention to use the AI tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust and perceived ease of use had limited impact on the intention to use the tools (especially the treatment recommendation tool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive technology readiness positively affected the intention to use one tool, while AI anxiety negatively impacted the intention to use both tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this means:
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-means&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our findings highlight the importance of perceived usefulness and social influence in driving the adoption of AI technology in mental health care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust and perceived ease of use may not be strong factors influencing the intention to use AI tools in this context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considering cognitive technology readiness can further promote the adoption of AI-enabled tools, while addressing AI anxiety is crucial in facilitating their utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study provides valuable insights for psychology students and early practitioners considering the integration of AI tools into their professional practice, and opens avenues for future research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h4 id=&#34;link-to-published-paperhttpshumanfactorsjmirorg20231e46859&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://humanfactors.jmir.org/2023/1/e46859&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to published paper&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#link-to-published-paperhttpshumanfactorsjmirorg20231e46859&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


